翻译：Iz      Tiogy      红豆包      小布拿拿
校对&总监：Iz
后期：斯人     时间轴：深夏桃子
更多动画  就在@欧美动漫汉化军团
《开心汉堡店》第五季第十五集
喷雾剂的解剖[化用《格蕾的解剖》 又名《实习医生格蕾》]
除虫害公司
周五啦  有什么伟大的周末计划吗
Friday! So, any big weekend plans?
*今晚是约会之夜*
*Date night tonight *
*出门享用晚餐*
*Gonna go out, get some food *
*小酌几杯*
*Have a few drinks *
*暂时忘掉孩子*
*Forget we have kids for a little bit *
到底是什么计划
What's the plan?
即使我想告诉你也说不出来
I couldn't tell you if I wanted to.
只有鲍鲍才知道
Only Bobby knows.
他计划了所有的事情
He planned the whole thing.
没错  计划中有晚餐  美酒
Yup. There will be dinner, drinks
还有娱乐项目
and entertainment.
三大项
The big three! Ha-cha-cha-cha!
我们
And...
回来了
we're home.
-那是什么  -班级宠物
- What's that? - The class pet.
这周末由我来照顾它
I'm taking care of it this weekend.
你不介意的
You're fine with it.
我...介意
I'm... not.
我在同意书上替你签过字了
The permission slip I signed for you
上面说你不介意
says you're fine with it.
而且还很喜欢
You're into it.
它怎么了
What's wrong with it?
毛质奇怪  身体抽抽  鼻子流水
Weird fur, seizures, runny nose,
眼睛流水  到处都黏糊糊的
runny eyes, runny everything.
是人都有几个缺点
Everybody's got their something.
就没有别人想收留它吗
There wasn't anyone else who wanted to take it?
-只有维恩  -谁是维恩
- Just Wayne. - Who's Wayne?
我们班上的同学  我们对这周末
Kid in my class. We had a tiny disagreement
应该谁来照顾这只栗鼠有场小的争论
about who should take the chinchilla home this weekend.
-不  不  不  -行  行  行
- No! No! No! No! No! - Yes! Yes! Yes! Yes!
看来  应该恭喜你了
Well, congratulations, I guess.
只是  别让它进我们的房间
Just, keep it out of our room.
知道知道  老爸
Yeah, yeah, okay, Dad.
你的小伙伴维恩有没有沮丧
Was your little friend Wayne upset?
没有  他很爽快的
No. He was easy breezy.
记住  睡觉时间是七点  别看太多电视
Remember, bedtime is 7:00, not too much TV,
别让他吃甜的  摸他的时候要顺着毛摸
no sugary snacks, and pet with the grain.
顺着毛摸
Pet with the grain!
好吧  别忘了
Okay, don't forget.
我和你们老爸今晚要出去
Your father and I are going out tonight,
所以你要照看大家  蒂娜  记得吗
so you're gonna babysit, Tina, right?
关于这点
About that.
我要和其她女生聊过
I was talking to some other girls,
你们知道干这种活的人都有薪水拿的吗
and did you know some people get paid to babysit?
天呐  这下有得缠了
Oh, boy, she's onto us.
好吧  我们来做个交易
Okay, let's start the negotiation.
一千美金和一个停车位
A thousand dollars and a parking space.
一小时三美金如何
How about three dollars an hour?
-好吧  成交  -每小时三美金
- Okay, deal. - Three dollars every hour?
我们都有份的  对吧  蒂娜
We get a cut of this, right, Tina?
好吧
Okay.
但等我们回到家
But you all got to be in bed
你们得都在床上了  否则一分没有
by the time we get home, or nobody sees a dime.
没问题  我们就算睡着也会去床上的
No problem... we can go to bed in our sleep.
鲍鲍
Bobby!
我好好奇你要带我去哪里
I'm excited to see where you're taking me.
琳  你没必要蒙上眼睛
Lin, you don't have to cover your eyes.
我从来没要求你这么做
I never asked you to do that.
我只是想要个大惊喜
I just want a big surprise.
看不到的时候总会觉得更加惊喜
And surprises are better when you're blind.
看看吧
Well, take a look.
我们到了
We're here!
-斯图尔兹餐厅  -更好的还在后面
-"Stoolz." - It gets better.
各位天才
Brainiacs!
我是你们的冷知识轰趴主持人戴夫
This is your trivia master Dave letting you know
还有不到一分钟冷知识轰趴之夜就要开始了
that we are less than one minute away from trivia night!
冷知识轰趴
Trivia night?
你说的更好的在哪儿  鲍勃
When does it get better, Bob?
刚才就是我想象中会变得更好的部分
Well, that was supposed to be the part where it got better.
-你不是很喜欢冷知识吗  -有吗
- Y-You love trivia. - I do?
我们多年前参加过一次冷知识轰趴
We played bar trivia that one time years ago.
-记得吗  -是吗
- Remember? - Yeah?
-我们玩得很开心  -是吗
- We had fun. - We did?
我反正觉得很开心
I thought we did.
我们团队的名字很有意思
We had a funny team name.
叫阿尔伯特・啤酒斯坦
We were Albert Beerstein.
-这有趣么  -是啊  很有趣
- That's funny? - Yes, it's funny!
可以有很多种解读的  琳
It works on many levels, Lin!
但是  你不喜欢的话  我们就换个地方
But, look, we can go somewhere else if you want to.
不必了  我们就在这里过吧
No, let's just get through date night.
-好吧  -好吧
- Right. - Okay.
-很好 好吧  -喝一杯
- Great. Fine. Yeah. - Yup, get a drink.
好了  冷知识高手们
Okay, trivia-meisters.
第一轮  第一个问题
Round one, question one.
我十四岁时  迷上了
When I was 14, I had a crush especial
波多黎各女演员罗西・培瑞兹
on Puerto Rican actress Rosie Perez.
我们赢了
Oh, we got this.
答案是电影名《黑白游龙》[培瑞兹主演]
It's gonna be White Men Can't Jump.
美国哪一年合并了波多黎各
In what year did the United States annex Puerto Rico?
是 一九...
Oh. it's, 19...
某某年  某某年
something, something.
你知道吗  第一个问题永远是最难的
You know what? The first question's always the hardest.
好吧  接下来的就没那么简单啦
All right, now that we got the easy one out of the way...
我去  我是说  肯定很好玩
Oh, crap. I mean, this will be fun.
是啊  很好玩  很好玩
Yeah, it's fun, it's fun.
就像做家庭作业  有趣的家庭作业
It's like homework, but-but fun homework.
有多少轮问题来着
How many rounds are there?
不...太多  但还是有一些
Not-not many, but many.
我只是想让你们知道
I just want you guys to know
虽然今晚我是你们拿薪水的保姆
that even though I'm your paid babysitter tonight,
但我还是你们的姐姐
I'm still your sister.
只是是拿钱的
But I'm getting paid.
不许把脚放沙发上
No feet on the couch.
但我还是你的姐姐
But I'm still your sister.
暂时的
For now.
我结婚后你就不是了
Until I get married off.
既然你跟了我
All right, so, when you're with me,
你就不叫撒尿小公主了
you're not called Princess Little Piddles.
你是阿忍
You are Shinobu.
你喜欢吗  我知道  这名字很棒
You like it? I know, it's great.
这位是酷奇・科比
This is Kuchi Kopi.
你们俩人都是小捣蛋
You're both little troublemakers.
你们在日本都很受欢迎
You're both huge in Japan.
我们肯定有好多话可以聊  开始吧
You probably have a lot to talk about... go!
聊轻松点的  别提离婚
Keep things light. Don't bring up your divorce.
也别提尼克松  还有电台司令
Or Nixon. Or Radiohead.
贝尔彻家
Belcher residence.
我父母今晚都在家  而且都是跆拳道黑带
Both my parents are home tonight and they're black belts.
找你的  露易丝
It's for you, Louise.
真的吗  你好
Really? Hello?
你好  露易丝  我是维恩
Hey, Louise. Wayne here.
撒尿小公主怎么样了
So how's Princess Little Piddles?
-很好  谢谢来电  再见  -等等
- Fine. Great talk. Bye-bye. - Wait!
-让小公主接电话  -什嘛
- Put Princess on the phone. - What?
-让撒尿小公主接电话  -为什么
- Put Princess Little Piddles on the phone! - Why?
撒尿小公主
Princess Little Piddles!
你能听到我的声音吗
Can you hear my voice?!
你还好吗
Are you okay?!
再见
Bye.
我去开门  因为我是负责人
I'll get it since I'm in charge.
我不在的时候  就由吉恩来负责
While I'm gone, Gene's in charge.
露易丝  如果吉恩搞不定
Louise, if Gene can't handle his duties,
就该你上了  妹妹
it's all you, sister.
我搞得定我的便便  谢谢
I can handle my doodies, thank you!
我阻止不了他
I couldn't stop him!
他像炮管一样一下就从我面前穿过去了
He barreled right past me like a really fast barrel!
天呐  维恩
Oh, my God, Wayne,
你是在我家门外打的电话吗
You were calling from outside my house?
出笼子了  出笼子了
Out of cage! Out of cage!
你太小题大做了  维恩
Okay, you're acting nuts, Wayne.
你是想说尽职尽责吗
Oh, you mean nuts for responsibility?!
我是想说你疯了  傻了  脑子进水了
Like nut, crazy, bad, rotten nut!
你是想说我超级靠谱  帅到抓狂
Responsible handsome head nuts maybe?!
不  不对  就是疯子
No, no way! Just nuts!
不  是帅到抓狂
No, handsome nuts!
一词多义  nut也有坚果的意思
-我知道坚果  和腰果差不多  -二位
- I know nuts! No, like cashews! - Excuse me!
我不想打扰你们这段超有聊的对话
I hate to interrupt a productive dialog,
但是栗鼠去哪了
but where'd the chinchilla go?
他就在这附近的某处
He's around here somewhere.
别尖叫了  帮忙找找  维恩
Stop screaming and help me look, Wayne!
前门为什么开着
Why is the front door open?
也许上帝关上了一扇窗
Maybe God closed a window?
栗鼠  好恶心
Chinchilla! Disgusting!
不要  不要  不要  不要
Oh, no, no, no, no!
妈妈
Hey, mama!
他在那里
There he is!
-你好  小家伙  -是乔纳斯
- Hey, little, guy. - It's Jonas.
太好了  他把它带回来了
Oh, good, he's bringing him back.
乔纳斯  你好
Jonas! Hey!
你捡到了我们的栗鼠  谢谢你
You found our chinchilla! Thank you!
什么  我听不见你说什么  再见
What? I can't hear you! Bye!
不要  不要  等等  等等
No! No! No! No! Wait! Wait! Wait!
不要
No!
天呐  刚刚发生了什么事
Oh, my God! What just happened?!
它跑掉了  加入了世上最逊飞车党的怀抱
It ran away and joined the worst biker gang in the world.
撒尿小公主被绑架了
Oh, Princess Little Piddles has been abducted!
这都是你的错  露易丝
This is all your fault, Louise!
什么  这都是你的错  维恩
What?! This is your fault, Wayne!
你闯入了我的家  还没关门
You barged in to my house and left the door open!
你也说我是闯进去的好吗
I was barging!
你见过哪个闯门的还负责关门啊
Bargers are not responsible for closing the door!
还不算太糟
It's not a disaster.
乔纳斯是雷吉熟食店的送餐员
Jonas is the delivery boy at Reggie's Deli.
我们去店里就行了
We'll just go to Reggie's.
我们不该出来的
We shouldn't be out!
我们应该回家
We should be back home!
爸妈没批准我带你们出门
I'm not certified for outdoor child care!
蒂娜  我们是由你监管
Tina, we're under your care,
但这只栗鼠由我监管
but this chinchilla is under my care,
严格来说  它也属于你的监管范围
which technically falls under your jurisdiction.
-对吧  -也许是吧
- Right? - I guess that's true.
也可能完全是胡说八道
Or it might not make any sense at all...
我们20分钟就回家
Well, we'll be back home in 20 minutes.
先去熟食店吧
All right, let's go to Reggie's.
完了  已经关门了
Crap! Reggie's is closed.
现在怎么办
Oh, now what?!
砸开窗户  进去做些三明治
We smash Reggie's window and make some sandwiches
然后再从长计议
and go from there.
不  我们去雷吉家
No, we go to where Reggie lives,
问他乔纳斯住哪
and we ask him where Jonas lives.
你们问乔纳斯住哪
You want to know where Jonas lives?
取号排队吧
Well, take a number.
开个玩笑  熟食店的幽默
Just kidding. Deli humor.
别胡闹了
Quit pussyfooting around!
告诉我们地址  雷吉
The address, Reggie!
乔纳斯去他朋友克雷家做作业了
Jonas is at his friend Clay's house doing homework.
克雷去乔纳斯家做作业了
Clay is at Jonas's house doing homework.
-什么情况  -难道不是吗
- What the...?  - Isn't he?
他们怎么可能同时在对方家里呢
How can they both be at each other's houses?
可能他们打通了时空连续统
Maybe they broke the space-time continuum.
肯定也是某种神秘的家庭作业
Must've been some homework.
也可能又是学生糊弄家长的借口
Unless it's an excuse teenagers tell their parents
他们不想让爸妈知道自己去了哪儿
when they don't want them to know where they're going.
但他们去哪里了呢
But where would that be?
那种青少年参加的秘密活动叫啥来着
A secret teen event of secrecy?
你是说派对吗
You mean a party?
没错  蒂娜  谢谢你
Yes! Tina, thank you!
那是泰迪吗
Is that Teddy?
*我*
*I... *
*真希望收音机没坏*
*Wish my radio worked.
不好  如果泰迪看到我们在外面
Oh, no! If Teddy sees us out of the house,
他肯定会告诉爸妈  所有人隐蔽
he'll tell Mom and Dad. Everyone hide!
我还以为看到哈维了呢
Oh, geez. Thought I saw Harvey.
差一点就被逮到  这样吧
Ah, that was close. Listen.
不如我们先回家  用烟斗通条
Why don't we go home, make a decoy chinchilla
和袜子做一只假的栗鼠拖延时间
out of pipe cleaners and socks to buy ourselves some time?
不蒂娜  我们要去派对
No, Tina, we're looking for a party.
关于高中派对  你知道哪些情况
What do you know about high school parties?
什么都不知道  不过我知道有个人
Nothing, but I might know someone
可能知道一些
who might know something.
你们这些小悲催们想干嘛
What do you maxi-sads want?
第一轮过后
Okay, after round one,
领先的是熟男联盟
in first place are the DILFs.
第二名是凯文老爹
In second place, Old Kevin.
最后一名  一个都没答对的是
And in last place, with no correct answers,
"圆桌约会二人组"
are the Date Nights of the Round Table.
本店有史以来第一对来约会的情侣
Hey! First couple ever here on a date!
看来爱情总是和智慧扯不到一块
I guess the romance doesn't revolve around knowing things,
因为他俩就没啥智慧
because they don't.
喂  说话注意点  "提问"先生
Hey, hey! Easy, Mr. Questions!
开个玩笑而已
Just kidding, just kidding.
我没开玩笑
I'm not kidding.
他们听不到我
They can't hear me.
他们啥都不知道
They don't know anything.
天  我们要输了
Oh, my God, we're losing.
还被鄙视了
And now we're getting heckled.
不然我们还是回家好了
I guess we can just go home.
好吧  我们走
All right, let's get out of here.
我先去下厕所
Let me just go to the bathroom.
第二轮  第一题
Round two, question one.
登山太愚蠢
Hiking is stupid.
请问阿帕拉契山道长多少英里
How many miles long is the Appalachian Trail?
还以为会有很多关于80年代电视剧的问题呢
I was hoping there'd be more questions about '80s TV shows.
鲍勃  我做坏事了
Bob, I did something bad.
-在厕所里  -不是
- In the bathroom?  - No!
我从戴夫的文件夹里偷到了答案
Look! I stole an answer sheet from Dave's folder!
-我们有答案了  -什么
- We got all the answers! - What?!
琳  你疯了吗  我们不能作弊
Lin, are you crazy? We can't cheat.
对  我们不能跟戴夫作弊
Oh, yeah, we don't want to cheat against Dave.
他是个多"好"的人啊
He's such a good guy.
快写答案  鲍勃
Write down the answer, Bob.
-快写  -好吧  好吧
- Write it down! - Okay, okay.
不要直接抄  要像你刚想出来一样
Not like that, like you just thought of it.
先看着天花板思考  然后说  嗯
You look at the ceiling, you say, "Hmm,"
然后再写
and then you look down.
对  就是这样
Yeah, yeah. That's it, that's it.
我也许能找到
I might be able to find out
乔纳斯那小子去了哪个高中派对
which high school party this Jonas kid is at,
但是我为啥要帮你们这帮小屁孩
but why would I want to help a bunch of babies
找你们的猫呢
get their cat back?
不是猫  是栗鼠
It's not a cat, it's a chinchilla!
对我来说除了狗  其它都是猫
Anything that's not a dog is a cat to me.
我们答应你随便一个要求  随时都行
We'll owe you. You name it. Anything, anytime.
如果我说要蒂娜在星期二凌晨三点
What if I want Tina to kiss a dirty flip-flop
亲一只发臭的夹脚拖呢
at 3:00 a.m. on a Tuesday?
-还是不要这么过...  -完全可以
- Let's not go crazy... - Of course. Yes. That.
不  不  不
No, no, no.
我还是再好好考虑一下给蒂娜的任务
I'm gonna think of something good to make Tina do later
等我心情不好的时候用
when I'm feeling really bad about myself.
不过就先这么说定了
But we've got a deal.
高科技都用上了
That's a lot of technology.
不就是有邮箱吗  我们晓得
We get it. You have e-mail.
我是在用社交媒体
I'm using social media
缩小乔纳斯的范围  看
to triangulate Jonas's whereabouts. Look.
乔纳斯是大卫・施纳贝尔的朋友
Jonas is friends with David Schnabel, who just tweeted
而他刚发推文艾特温妮莎・杰克逊
at Vanessa Jackson
说"凯西派对见"
"See you at Casey's party."
而莉拉尼・勒弗曾在她的秘密博客上说
And according to Leilani LeFelt's secret blog
她还以为没人发现她这博客呢
she thinks no one knows about,
乔纳斯在狂恋温妮莎
Jonas has a huge crash on Vanessa.
也就是说乔纳斯在凯西的派对  搞定
So that means Jonas is at Casey's party. Voila.
好吧各位  准备好  现在出发
All right, troops, wheels up, we're flying!
露易丝  我觉得还是不要去高中派对比较好
I-I don't think we can go to a high school party, Louise.
爸妈会杀了我的
Mom and Dad will kill me.
派对上会有高中男生哦
There'll be high school boys there.
好吧  就进去一会应该没事
Right. Maybe we can just do a quick pop-in.
等等  你以为自己能进去吗
Oh, wait, you think you're gonna get into that party?
你不可能进去的  我都进不去
Oh, you are never gonna get in. I wouldn't even get in,
我还是八年级最漂亮的女生呢
and I'm the hottest girl in eighth grade.
原来你上八年级啊
You're in eighth grade?
我还以为你都当妈了呢
I thought you were someone's mom.
相信我  苔米
Trust me, Tammy.
进去是最容易的事
Getting in is gonna be the easy part.
教师休息室我都不知去了多少回了
I've gotten into the teacher's lounge so many times
连自己的咖啡杯都有了
I have my own coffee mug there.
上面印着"我恨星期一"  太经典
It says "I Hate Mondays." Classic.
我要你们兑现承诺了
I'm cashing in my favor.
如果你能让我进去  我们就扯平
If you can get me into that party, we're even.
别磨叽了  我们的一分钟
Let's go! Every minute of our life
是栗鼠的五分钟啊
is five minutes of a chinchilla's life!
这就是我们进那烂派对的门票了
Here's our ticket into this poop show.
垃圾能有什么用
How is trash gonna help us?
哎  维恩  学着点
Oh, Wayne. Watch and learn.
-有人点了  -你说什么
- Well, someone did.  - What?
你刚是不是说了"我们没点披萨"
Did you say, "We didn't order any pizza"?
-没有  -有人点了
- No. - Well, someone did.
如果我不送的话
And old man pizza boss is gonna have my ass
披萨店那老家伙会找我麻烦的
if I don't deliver it.
洗手间在哪里
Where's the bathroom?
-从那条路过去  -谢了
- Down that way. - Thanks.
我30分钟内就出来
I'll be out of there in 30 minutes or less.
撑住啊  阿特拉斯  我们来了
Hang on, Atlas. We're coming, buddy.
阿特拉斯是谁
Who's Atlas?
那是我给撒尿小公主取的别名
It's my secret name for Princess Little Piddles.
是吗  我叫它阿忍
Really? I call him Shinobu.
撒尿小公主
Princess Little Piddles...
这名字太扯了
it just isn't right.
对吧  不该让四年级学生取名
I know. Fourth graders shouldn't be in charge of names.
还有决定它的性别
Or sex determination.
拜托  它有蛋蛋哎
He has testicles for God's sake!
是啊  我告诉他们了那是蛋蛋
I know! I told them, "Guys, those are testicles!"
没人信
No one believed me!
非说那是屁股蛋
Everyone thought they were butt boobs!
真不敢相信竟然成了
I can't believe that worked.
干得漂亮  吉恩
Well done, Gene.
你是真的在上厕所吗
Are you going to the bathroom?
我能说不是吗
No?
哎哟我去
Oh, my God!
高中派对怎么会有小动物的容身之处
A high school party is no place for a small animal!
他们没准正在用它
They're probably playing Spin the Chinchilla
玩"旋转栗鼠"呢
with him right now!
专注一点
Let's just focus here.
如果你是带着栗鼠的青少年
If you were a teenager with a chinchilla,
你会在哪儿
where would you be?
栗鼠动漫大会
Chinchilla-con.
这是我们第一次参加高中派对
So this is our first high school party.
用心感受这一刻
Let's savor this moment.
我发现高中男生的屁股都高一些
High school boys' butts are higher up, I'm noticing.
帅哥接近预告  两点钟方向
Okay, incoming teen dream, two o'clock...
不知道准确不
if I'm using that term correctly, which I don't know,
因为我不太会看指针表
because I actually can't tell time on those round clocks.
调情模式开启  走你
Ring the flirt alarm, here I go.
叮铃铃  叮铃铃
Yeah, it's just like ding-dong, ring-a-ding,
爆发吧小宇宙
let this rip.
你们几个是几年级的
Hey, what grade are you guys in?
算了吧  拜拜
Forget it. Bye.
我感觉不到我的胳膊了  我动不了了
I can't feel my arms! I can't move!
天呐  他比我爸还高
Oh, God, he was taller than my dad!
天呐  又有个人来了
Oh, God, another one's coming!
在网上  你可以成为任何人
On the Internet, you can be whoever you want,
没人会知道的
and no one will ever know.
"调制调解器"这个词是怎么来的
Where does the word "Modem" Come from?
调制解调器:又名猫,用于网络连接
要故意答错吗
Should we get this one wrong?
以免显得太可疑
Just to not look suspicious?
不  我们知道这个
No. We know this one.
我们不知道  我们这是作弊
We don't know it... we're cheating.
现在我们知道了
Well, now we know it,
-我们不会错了  -好吧
- and we're not getting it wrong. - Okay.
你知道答案吗  熟男联盟
You know the answer, DILFs?
凯文老爹呢  我们知道哦
Old Kevin? Because we do.
-琳  -怎么了
- Lin. - What?
-你在干嘛  -我在学猫啊
- What is that? - It's a modem.
我在对他们学猫叫
I'm making modem noises at them.
这  这样更像
It-it's more like this.
好了  猫叫的真好
Okay, good modem noises,
圆桌约会二人组
Date Nights of the Round Table.
回到问题
Now back to the questions.
够了  够了
Okay, okay!
-蒂娜  -怎么了
- Tina. - What?
我想放屁了
I have to fart.
害怕的屁  我...我忍不了了
It's a fear fart. I... I can't hold it.
苔米  不  你不能在高校派对上放屁
Tammy, no! You can't fart at a high school party.
我知道  你以为我不知道吗
I know that! Don't you think I know that?!
好吧  交给我吧  亲爱的
Okay, I'm gonna fix this, honey.
你能紧紧地忍住
Can you hold it real tight
直到我把你搬到窗户边吗
until I get you to a window?
我现在就把你抬过去
I'm gonna pick you up now.
轻点
Gentle.
别挤我
Don't squeeze.
不好意思  让一让
Excuse us. Coming through.
只是两个正常的青少年在享受派对
Just a couple of normal teenagers partying.
你好  最近好吗
Hi. How are you?
-最近过的好吗  -放吧  放吧
- How are you doing? - Go, go.
蒂娜  你真的救了我一命
Tina, you literally just saved my life.
我至死都不会忘记的
I am not gonna forget this until the day I die.
-那真是  -天呐  这妹子放屁了
- That's so... - Oh, my God, this girl farted!
-在这  就在这  -什么
- Right here, over here! - What?
我开玩笑的  开个玩笑  开个玩笑
I'm kidding, I'm kidding, I'm kidding.
没人听到我们
Nobody's listening to us.
乔纳斯  找到你了
Jonas... bingo.
敲敲门
Knock-knock.
是谁啊  你们啊
Who's there? you guys.
你们是谁啊
You guys who?
对了  你们不能来这儿的
That's right, you're not supposed to be here.
把我们的栗鼠还回来  乔纳斯
Give us the chinchilla, Jonas.
那是我们的
It's ours.
你难道不知道它是四年级的班级宠物么
It's the fourth-grade class pet, for crying out loud.
什么  好吧  抱歉  我不知道
What? Oh, well, sorry, I didn't know that.
我以为他是小精灵呢  我当时还想
I thought he was a gremlin, and I was like,
"我去  小精灵是真的吗"
"What? Gremlins are real?"
-总之  我把它送给温妮莎了  -什么
- Anyway, I gave him to Vanessa. - What?! What?!
温妮莎在哪儿
Where's Vanessa?
她带着它  和几个朋友走了
She took it, went off with some of her friends,
她们说  "仅限女生  除了这三个"
and they were like, "Girls only, except these three guys."
他们去哪了
Where did they go?
我不知道
I don't know.
他们好像说是要滑旱冰
They were talking about going roller-skating.
滑旱冰都去哪儿
Wherever you do that.
溜冰场吗  难道是
The roller rink, maybe?
对哦
Oh, yeah.
我要扇你了
Oh, I'm gonna slap you.
什么
What?
人家靠脸吃饭的
My moneymaker!
来  让我看一下
Here, let me see that for a second.
你们找到乔纳斯了
Oh, you found Jonas.
你好  乔纳斯
Hi, Jonas.
是你啊  妹子
You, girl.
我以为你不记得了呢
I was afraid you wouldn't remember me.
是不是意味着栗鼠找到了
Does this mean we got the chinchilla back?
老妈老爸随时可能到家
Because Mom and Dad could be home any minute.
没有  乔纳斯送人了
No. Jonas gave him away,
他现在在溜冰场呢
and now he's at a roller rink.
乔纳斯  温妮莎长什么样
Jonas, what does Vanessa look like?
我不知道  她有头发  穿了裤子
I don't know. She has hair and pants.
描述的真好  你应该给联邦调查局工作
Great description... you should work for the FBI.
听着  你要跟我们一起去指认她
Listen, you're coming with us to point out who she is.
为什么我要这么做
Why would I do that?
你俩应该在一起
You guys belong together.
你这样  她那样
You have the thing, she has her thing.
是啊  同性也相吸的
Yeah, it's the opposite of "Opposites attract."
该你乔纳斯上场了
This is Jonas time.
你就是为了这一刻而存在的
This is what you've been training for.
你必须和我们一起去
You got to go with us.
天呐  走起吧
Oh, my God. Let's go!
我来了  阿忍
I'm coming, Shinobu.
我来了  阿特拉斯
I'm coming, Atlas.
我来了  滑冰场小卖部的热狗
I'm coming, roller rink snack bar hot dogs!
好了  到溜冰场了
All right, there's the rink.
我们去救回我们的栗鼠吧
Let's go get our chinchilla.
天呐  你说他们那里
Oh, God, you don't think
不会有闪光灯吧  对不对
they have strobe lights in there, do you?
也许吧  怎么了
Probably. Why?
他看见闪光灯会抽筋的
Strobe lights give him seizures.
对了  闪光灯事件
Oh, right, the strobe light incident.
阿方索干嘛带闪光灯去展示讲述活动课
Why did Alfonz bring a strobe light to show and tell?
因为那是他爷爷发明的
'cause his grandfather invented it.
天呐  难道又是泰迪吗
Oh, my God, is that Teddy again?
泰式炒河粉真不适合开车吃
Pad thai is not good driving food.
大家不许动
Everyone freeze!
我们为什么不动
Why are we freezing?
我们不动  他就看不见了
If we don't move, he can't see us.
-真的吗  -也许
- Is that true? - Maybe.
摒住呼吸
Hold your breath!
完蛋  我刚想起来
Oh, shoot, I just remembered
我对花生过敏
I'm allergic to peanuts.
我会没事的  我会没事的
I'll be all right. I'll be all right.
天呐  真起作用了
Oh, my God, it worked.
蒂娜简直是个巫师
Tina's a wizard.
做点别的吧
Do something else.
给我变一件牛仔夹克
Make a jean jacket appear on me.
吉恩夹克["牛仔"与"吉恩"同音]
Jean jacket!
现在是最后一轮了
It's time for the final round.
难以相信  看起来蠢兮兮的约会二人组
And incredibly, the seemingly dimwitted Date Nighters
飞速冲到了第一名
have rocketed into first place.
约会二人组万岁
Yeah, Date Nighters!
我们聪明又可爱
We're smart, and cute!
比熟男联盟更可爱
Cuter than the DILFs!
好了  安静点  第一个问题
All right, okay, settle down. Question one:
我没做过木工也没上过船
I've never been a carpenter or on a boat,
但库尔特・拉塞尔在1987年
but Kurt Russell did both
哪部电影里把两件事都做了
in what 1987 movie?
琳  答案呢
Lin, where's the answer sheet?
不  掉了
Oh, no, it fell.
天呐  捡回来  琳  离你更近
Oh, God, get it, Lin. You're closer.
我知道  我知道
Shh, I got it, I got it.
哎呀呀  我掉了点豆泥
I dropped some hummus.
你好  我就来捡那豆泥的
Hello, just getting that hummus there.
-好吧  -我们爱豆泥
- Okay. - We love hummus.
那是什么
Hey, what's that?
-什么  -那是答案
- What? - That's an answer sheet.
-不  -是的  肯定是
- Nah. - Uh, yeah, definitely.
-不不不  -你们作弊  你们作弊
- No. No, no. - You were cheating, you're cheating.
-骗子  -没人作弊
- Cheaters! - No one's cheating.
-不  -大骗子
- No. - Total cheaters!
彻头彻尾的骗子
Full-on cheaters!
好吧  实话告诉你
Okay, you know what?
我们就是作弊了
We were cheating.
我带我老婆来约会
I took my wife here on date.
我们一年就约会三次
We have about three of these a year.
过得好的时候
In a good year.
我带她来到这个冷知识轰趴
And I brought her to bar trivia.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
你是帮凶  戴夫
And you didn't help, Dave.
你让我们觉得自己很蠢
You made us feel stupid,
就因为我们不知道
just because we didn't know the answers
任何问题的答案
to any of the questions.
我知道这对凯文来说很好笑
I know that was fun for Kevin.
我知道  我知道
I know, I know.
但我老婆找到个办法
But my wife found a way
让今晚变得有趣  可是  妈的
to make this date night fun, and, damn it,
我不觉得抱歉
I'm not sorry about that.
真甜蜜
So sweet.
你俩给我出去  黛博拉
You're out of here! Deborah!
不  它
No, it...
手拿开  黛博拉
Hands off, Deborah.
抱歉  琳
I'm sorry, Lin.
那真是
That was,
-值了  -好激烈
- worth it. - Hot one.
下次约会夜  我们去KTV作弊
Next date night, let's cheat at karaoke.
好了  乔纳斯
All right, Jonas,
温妮莎在哪
where's Vanessa?
我的栗鼠在哪
Where's my chinchilla?
我们的栗鼠
Our chinchilla.
温妮莎  我此生挚爱
Okay, Vanessa, love of my life.
我们来找找  她在那呢
Let's see. There she is!
快上  快上
Let's go, let's go!
该我滑进温妮莎心里了
Time to roll my way into Vanessa's heart.
温妮莎  栗鼠呢
Vanessa, where's the chinchilla?
-啥  -撒尿小公主
- What? - Princess Little Piddles!
撒尿啥
What's "Piddles"?
我们的班级宠物
He's our class pet.
对不起  小朋友们
Oh, I'm sorry, little kids,
那个保安
but that security guard
出40块跟我买
offered me 40 bucks for it.
天呐  你怎么能那样
Oh, my God! How could you?
很容易啊
It was easy.
他说  "给  40块"
He was like, "Here's $40."
然后我说  "拿走吧"
And I was like, "Here you go."
我们走吧
Come on!
温妮莎  那个叫乔纳斯的娃喜欢你
Oh, Vanessa, that kid Jonas likes you,
你应该给他一次机会  不给也行
and you should give him a chance. Or not.
-随便你  -啥  我听不清
- Your call. - What? I can't hear you.
音乐太大声了  我回去滑冰了
The music's too loud. I got to skate.
温妮莎
Hey, Vanessa!
等等我
Wait for me!
-先生  -什么
- Hey, sir? - Yeah.
你能把我往那女孩那儿推一把吗
Can you push me towards that girl over there?
好吧
All right.
他摸我屁股
He touched my butt.
打扰了  你好
Excuse me, hi.
你花40块买的那玩意儿  是我们的
That thing you paid $40 for, it's ours.
你们也抽大麻
You guys smoke weed?
不是  你花40块买的那只栗鼠
No, the chinchilla you paid $40 for.
啥  不不不
What? No, no, no.
那是我要送给房东的礼物
That's gonna be a present for my landlord.
我这个月的房租还差点
I'm a little short on rent this month.
你为啥不把那40块给他
Why didn't you give him the $40?
你真聪明
Hey, you're a smart kid.
-你五分钟前在哪儿  -那边
- Where were you five minutes ago? - Over there.
抱歉了  伙计  栗鼠已经是
Sorry, buddy, but the chinchilla already belongs
勒邦姿老师四年级班的财产了
to Miss Labonz's fourth-grade class.
看来我只能从了
I guess I have to do the right thing.
你有40块吗
You have 40 bucks?
我们可以给你写张支票  你有支票吗
We can write you a check. Do you have a check?
我有
I do.
咋了
What?
如果你是一只栗鼠
Okay, if you were a chinchilla,
一只不愿乖乖呆在盒子里的
and you were a rascally little son of a bitch
小杂种  你会去哪儿
that wouldn't stay in a box, where would you be?
-不  -该死
- No! - Damn it!
-阿忍  过来  -老鼠  出来
- Here, Shinobu. - Here, thingy.
-阿特拉斯  阿特拉斯  -老鼠老鼠
- Atlas, Atlas. - Here, thingy, thingy.
-哈维尔  -阿忍
- Javier. - Shinobu.
-你去哪儿了  -等下  那个是他吗
- Where are you? - Oh, wait, is that him?
还是一只松垮垮毛茸茸的滑冰鞋
Or is that a loose furry skate?
他在那儿会被压死的
He's gonna get killed out there!
看路  借过
Look out, coming through!
闪开  闪开
Move it, people, move it!
是的  各位
You know what that means.
大鞭时间到啦
Time for The Whip!
坚持住  阿忍
Hang on, Shinobu!
我来保护你  阿特拉斯
I'll protect you, Atlas!
你还好吗
You okay?
还好
I'm okay.
我们快走  快  走走走
Let's get out of here, quick. Go, go, go!
看来有人转吐了呢
We have a vomit situation.
要小心咯  滑手们
Look out, skaters,
地板一湿就可滑了
the floor gets slippery when wet.
温妮莎
Vanessa!
不
No!
好恶心
Oh, gross!
天呐
Oh, God.
我现在没那么喜欢她了
I like her less now.
拜托让老爸老妈还没回家
Please let Mom and Dad not be home.
爸  妈
Mom? Dad?
谢天谢地  他们还没回
Oh, thank God, they're not home.
维恩  我们做到了
Well, Wayne, we did it.
是的
Yeah, we did.
你在冰场上表现得很勇敢
You were great out there on the rink.
-你成功了  大获成功  -你也是
- You came through, big-time. - You, too.
那么  我来抱着阿特拉斯
So I'll hold Atlas
你去收拾他的东西
while you go collect his things.
我天  我们为了找回他经历了这么多
Oh, my God, after all we just went through to get him back,
到头来你还这幅德行
you're still acting like this?
还要把他带回家吗
You still want to take him home?
别忘了拿他的水壶
Don't forget his water bottle.
动作快点  今天晚上该给他讲故事的
And, hurry, 'cause if he's gonna get a story tonight,
我得赶紧带他回家
I have to get him home soon.
这样好了  我们让他自己选择
You know what, why don't we just let him choose
他想跟谁呆在一起
who he wants to stay with?
这一年来我每周都照顾他
I've cared for him every weekend for a year,
我很确信他会选谁
so I think I know who he's gonna pick.
很好
Perfect.
你站那边  我站这边
You stand there, I'll stand here,
蒂娜  把他放在中间
Put him down in the middle, Tina.
-好吧  -快到维恩这来  阿特拉斯
- Okay. - Come to Wayne, Atlas.
-过来  阿忍  -来  到维恩这来
- Come here. Shinobu. - Come on, come to Wayne.
快来  宝贝儿
Come here, baby.
过来  阿特拉斯
Come on, Atlas. Atlas.
快来  来来来
Come here, come, come, come.
欧耶
Yes!
看见没  维恩
Take that, Wayne.
他喜欢的是我  不是你
He loves me, not you.
他受够你那些无聊的规则了
He's sick of your boring rules!
好吧  他自己做了选择
Okay, he's made his choice.
那我就回家了
Well, I guess I'll get going.
周末愉快
Have a good weekend.
你不想和阿忍道个别吗
Don't you want to say good-bye to Shinobu?
不了  我  我们周一见
Oh, no, I'll... I'll see you Monday.
感觉没我想象的好呢
That didn't feel as great as I thought it would.
当然  还是很爽的
I mean, it still feels great,
只是没那么爽
but just not as great.
我看是你让维恩以为
My theory is that Wayne is really sad
栗鼠不爱他  让他伤心了
because you made him think the chinchilla doesn't love him.
我们何不迅速上床
Why don't we all go get in bed really fast,
躺在床上琢磨吉恩的话对不对呢  快快快
and think about whether Gene is right. Go, go, go!
嗨  为啥有个小孩哭着从我们家跑出去了
Hi. Why did some kid just run out of here crying?
总是有小孩从我家哭着跑出去
There's always kids running out of here crying.
-你还不睡在干嘛  -嗨老爸  嗨老爸
- What are you still doing up? - Oh, hi, Mom. Hi, Dad.
我们绝对没出去
We weren't out or anything.
-我们整晚都在家  -好吧
- We were home all night. - Okay.
可你这样一说反而让我觉得是不是...
You saying that makes me think you maybe...
算了  这次算在我头上
Hey, you know what, this one's on me.
你们不用付我工资了
You don't even have to pay me.
高中生派对  什么东西
High school party? What?
等  等下
W-Wait, hold on a second.
露易丝咋了
What's wrong with Louise?
露易丝  亲爱的  你还好吗
Louise, honey, you okay?
我想我需要去个地方
I think I need a ride somewhere.
不
No.
你来做什么
What are you doing here?
嗨  你走以后
Hey, so after you left,
阿忍就变得很沮丧  没精神
Shinobu seemed real down and kind of off.
他不打喷嚏了
He wasn't sneezing or anything,
也不抽抽了
like, not a single seizure.
真的吗
Really?
所以呢  我想他是想你了
Anyway, I guess maybe he missed you.
-真的吗  -我觉得
- He did? - I just don't think
他在我家是不会过得开心的
he's gonna be happy at our place.
再说  我爸头脑简单  掌握不好力道
Plus, my dad's simple and doesn't know his own strength.
看得出来
Oh, I can see that.
你爸一看就是那种见东西就坐的人
I mean, your dad looks like he'd sit on anything.
他的确啥都坐过
Oh, he has.
我人就在这儿
I'm right here.
所以还是你来照顾他吧
So you better just take him.
我觉得他根本不喜欢我
I don't think he even likes me.
别闹  配合点
Stop it, play along.
周一告诉我他情况如何  好吗
Tell me how it goes on Monday, will you?
好的  谢了  拜
Okay, thanks, bye.
拜
Bye.
不错啊  露易丝
That was nice, Louise.
真的很贴心呢
That was really, really sweet.
我知道
I know.
我和你老妈今晚在冷知识轰趴上作弊了
You know, me and your mom cheated at trivia tonight.
-真的吗  -是不是很
- Really? - Yup. Impressed?
你脑子进水了吗
What's wrong with you?
干嘛带她去冷知识轰趴
You took her to trivia?
感觉你唬弄了老妈一个约会
Sounds like you cheated Mom out of a date.
这才是我的露易丝
There's my girl.
*今晚是约会之夜*
*Date night tonight*
*出门享用晚餐*
*Gonna go out, get some food *
*喝点小酒  暂时忘记孩子们*
*Have a few drinks, forget we have kids for a little bit*
*约会之夜*
*Date night tonight, yeah *
*出门享用晚餐*
*Gonna go out, get some food *
*喝点小酒  暂时忘记孩子们*
*Have a few drinks, forget we have kids for a little bit *
*出门享用晚餐*
*Gonna go out, get some food *
*喝点小酒  暂时忘记孩子们*
*Have a few drinks, forget we have kids for a little bit *
*这就是我们*
*It's just what we do *
*约会之夜*
*Date night, date night, date night *
*出门*
*Gonna go out...*